Register of the Commission for Relief in Belgium Records, 1914-1930
Hoover Institution Archives
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, n.d.
  - Portraits of Ben S. Allen, William C. Ames, Robert Arrowsmith, Frank Angell, Fernand Baetens, Lindon W. Bates, Pope Benedict XV, Henry Percy Bradford, Milton M. Brown, Floyd S. Bryant, German Bulle, Oliver C. Carmichael, Charles H. Carstairs, Philip H. Chadbourn, William H. Chadbourn, Frederick H. Chatfield, Oswald Chew, Archibald D. Clarke, Charles R. Clason, A. N. Connett, Marie Corelli, Edward D. Curtis, Henry F. Cutler, James Dangerfield, Jr., Thomas B. Dawson, Oliver W. De Gruchy, Armand Dulait, Harry L. Dunn, William McKee Dunn, Robert M. Dutton, William C. Edgar, Elisabeth, Queen of the Belgians, Nina Franstead Eloesser, John H. Fleming, Alfred C. B. Fletcher, John A. Gade, Frank H. Gailor, James W. Gerard, Hugh Gibson, J. L. Glenn, Jr., Prentiss N. Gray, Joseph C. Green, Donald M. Gregory, George McLean Harper, Charles Hawkins, William L. Honnold, William B. Jackson, René L. Jensen, Amos D. Johnson, Jr., Henry Johnson, Thomas H. Jones, Vernon L. Kellogg, St. Alban Kite, Tracy B. Kittredge, J. W. Krueger, Charles N. Lathrop, Charles N. Leach, Maurice Le Blau, Dr. LeBoeuf, E. T. Liefeld, William Palmer Lucas, Ridgely Lytle, Jr., Charles H. McCloskie, Alfred L. Malabre, Lester D. Mapes, Arthur B. Maurice, Frederick W. Meert, Dudley S. Morgan, David T. Nelson, Francis D. Neville, Earl D. Osborn, Thomas E. Oliver, Maurice Pate, William A. Percy, Philip S. Platt, William Babcock Poland, Philip B. K. Potter, Henry S. Pratt, Lewis Richards, Edgar Rickard, A. B. Ruddock, S. S. Seward, Jr., Richard H. Simpson, Gilchrist B. Stockton, Carlos H. Stone, E. Coppée Thurston, Frederick C. Thwaits, Henry Van Dyke, Marquis de Villalobar, M. van Volenhoven, Mrs. Humphry Ward, Robert H. Warren, Laurence C. Wellington, Almon C. Whiting, Francis C. Wickes, Edgar Williams, Robert Withington, and Carl A. Young (Box 617)
  - Portraits of Frank Angell, David P. Barrows, Lindon W. Bates, Mrs. Lindon W. Bates, Louis Belrose, Carleton G. Bowden, Bennett H. Branscomb, H. Gordon Chasseaud, A. W. Clark, Frederick Eckstein, Nina Franstead Eloesser, George I. Gay, Herbert Hoover, Edward Eyre Hunt, Will Irwin, Henry Johnson, Tracy B. Kittredge, Maurice Le Blau, Compton Mackenzie, Pierre Mali, Robert Maverick, Frederick W. Meert, C. B. Murdock, Maurice Pate, Gardner Richardson, Charles F. Scott, and William H. Sperry; group portraits of Commission for Relief in Belgium staff members; and prints of Commission for Relief in Belgium offices and office buildings in London and Rotterdam (Box 618)
  - Prints of relief ships, including many scenes of loading and unloading grain by barge (Box 619-623)
  - Prints of dockside loading and unloading of relief ships, and cargo holds (Box 624)
  - Prints of Commission for Relief in Belgium warehouses; railway and truck transportation of food relief; and groups of Belgian children (Box 625)
  - Prints of groups of Belgian children (Box 626)
  - Prints of Belgian refugees; scenes of relief distribution; and caricatures (Box 627)
  - General and miscellaneous prints (Box 628)
  - Portraits of Ben S. Allen, Frank Angell, Robert Arrowsmith, Fernand Baetens, George Barr Baker, David P. Barrows, Lindon W. Bates, Mrs. Lindon W. Bates, Louis Belrose, Carlton G. Bowden, Frank P. Brackett, Bennett H. Branscomb, Milton M. Brown, Walter Lyman Brown, Floyd S. Bryant, German Bulle, and James A. St. Amour (Box 629, Folder A)
  - Portraits of Oliver C. Carmichael, Charles H. Carstairs, Philip H. Chadbourn, William H. Chadbourn, Frederick H. Chatfield, Oswald Chew, A. W. Clark, Charles R. Clason, Thomas O. Connett, Oscar T. Crosby, and Edward D. Curtis (Folder B)
  - Portraits of James Dangerfield, Jr., Thomas B. Dawson, Oliver W. De Gruchy, Armand Dulait, Harry L. Dunn, William McKee Dunn, Robert M. Dutton, Frederick Eckstein, Nina Franstead Eloesser, Alfred C. B. Fletcher, Frank H. Gailor, and George I. Gay (Folder C)
  - Portraits of Carleton B. Gibson, Hugh Gibson, J. L. Glenn, Jr., Prentiss N. Gray, Joseph C. Green, Donald M. Gregory, Warren Gregory, Dudley B. Gunn, William M. Gwynn, Guillermo Hall, and William Chapman Hall (Folder D)
  - Portraits of Herbert F. Hamilton, Dr. Hannicart, George McLean Harper, Emil Holman, William L. Honnold, Herbert Hoover, R. T. House, Edward Eyre Hunt, George S. Jackson, Robert A. Jackson, William B. Jackson, René L. Jensen, Amos D. Johnson, Jr., Henry Johnson, and Thomas H. Jones (Folder E)
  - Portraits of Vernon L. Kellogg, St. Alban Kite, Tracy B. Kittredge, Charles N. Leach, Dr. LeBoeuf, E. T. Liefeld, William Palmer Lucas, John F. Lucey, Ridgely Lytle, Jr., Alfred L. Malabre, Pierre Mali, Lester D. Mapes, and Arthur B. Maurice (Folder F)
  - Portraits of Howard McClenahan, Charles H. McCloskie, Robert Maverick, Frederick W. Meert, Dudley S. Morgan, C. B. Murdock, David T. Nelson, Francis D. Neville, Thomas E. Oliver, Thomas J. Orbison, Earl D. Osborn, Scott H. Paradise, Maurice Pate, William A. Percy, Philip S. Platt, William Babcock Poland, and Francis H. Potter (Folder G)
  - Portraits of Philip B. K. Potter, Henry S. Pratt, Lewis Richards, Gardner Richardson, Edgar Rickard, A. B. Ruddock, Millard K. Shaler, John L. Simpson, Richard H. Simpson, William H. Sperry, T. Harwood Stacy,Gilchrist B. Stockton, Carlos H. Stone, William W. Stratton, E. Coppée Thurston, and Frederick C. Thwaits (Folder H)
  - Portraits of Clare M. Torrey, William Hallam Tuck, Julius A. Van Hee, John Brodhead Van Schaick, Marquis de Villalobar, M. van Volenhoven, Robert H. Warren, Laurence C. Wellington, Brand Whitlock, Caspar Whitney, and Francis C. Wickes (Box 630, Folder I)
  - Portraits of Dr. Wiley, Edgar Williams, L. C. Wilson, Robert Withington, Carl A. Young, and unidentified persons (Folder J)
  - Prints of Belgian refugees, and Belgian workshops (Folder K)
  - Prints of Belgian schools, and groups of students (Folder L-M)
  - Prints of relief ships (Folder N)
  - Prints of warehouses (Folder O)
  - Prints of food distribution in Belgium (Box 631, Folder P-Q)
  - Prints of various scenes in Belgium (Folder R)
  - Prints of tokens of Belgian appreciation (Folder S)
  - Group portraits of Commission for Relief in Belgium personnel (Folder T-U)
  - Portraits of Albert I, King of the Belgians; Leopold, Crown Prince of Belgium; Charles, Prince of Belgium; and Henriette, Duchesse de Vendome; and prints of miscellaneous subjects (Folder V)
  - Negatives of group portraits of Commission for Relief in Belgium personnel (Folder W)
  - Prints of Belgian school children (Box 632, Folder mX-mY)
  - Portraits of German Bulle, William C. Edgar, Horace Fletcher, Emile Francqui, Robert A. Jackson, and William H. Sperry (Folder mZ)
  - Group portraits of Commission for Relief in Belgium personnel (Folder mAA-mBB)
  - Prints and drawings of Commission for Relief in Belgium operations (Folder mCC)
  - Prints of demonstrations of Belgian appreciation (Folder mDD)
  - Prints of Herbert Hoover with Commission for Relief in Belgium personnel, and unidentified persons (Folder mEE)
  - Prints of miscellaneous subjects (Folder mFF)
  - Prints of relief ships (Box 633, Folder GG-II)
  - Prints of food distribution in Belgium (Folder JJ)
  - Prints of groups of Belgian schoolchildren (Folder KK)
  - Prints of war damage in France (Folder LL)
  - Prints of the Commission for Relief in Belgium Lace Department, and miscellaneous subjects (Folder MM)
  - Portraits of Frank Angell, Robert Arrowsmith, Fernand Baetens, David P. Barrows, Lindon W. Bates, W. G. Beach, Louis Belrose, Carleton G. Bowden, Frank P. Brackett, Henry Percy Bradford, Bennett H. Branscomb, Milton M. Brown, Walter Lyman Brown, Floyd S. Bryant, and German Bulle (Box 634, Folder NN)
  - Portraits of Oliver C. Carmichael, Philip H. Chadbourn, William H. Chadbourn, Frederick H. Chatfield, Oswald Chew, A. W. Clark, Charles R. Clason, A. N. Connett, Thomas O. Connett, Morris W. Croll, Oscar T. Crosby, Edward D. Curtis, and Henry F. Cutler (Folder OO)
  - Portraits of James Dangerfield, Jr., Thomas B. Dawson, Oliver W. De Gruchy, Harry M. Dobson, Armand Dulait, Henry L. Dunn, William McKee Dunn, Robert M. Dutton, Frederick Eckstein, and Alfred C. B. Fletcher (Folder PP)
  - Portraits of John A. Gade, Frank H. Gailor, Carleton B. Gibson, J. L. Glenn, Jr., Prentiss N. Gray, Joseph C. Green, Donald M. Gregory, Warren Gregory, Dudley B. Gunn, and William M. Gwynn (Folder QQ)
  - Portraits of Guillermo Hall, William Chapman Hall, Herbert F. Hamilton, Dr. Hannicart, George McLean Harper, Charles Hawkins, Dannie N. Heineman, Emil Holman, William L. Honnold, R. T. House, and Edward Eyre Hunt (Folder RR)
  - Portraits of George S. Jackson, Robert A. Jackson, William B. Jackson, René L. Jensen, Amos D. Johnson, Jr., Henry Johnson, Thomas H. Jones, Vernon L. Kellogg, St. Alban Kite, Tracy B. Kittredge, Charles N. Lathrop, Charles N. Leach, Dr. LeBoeuf, E. T. Liefeld, William Palmer Lucas, and Ridgely Lytle, Jr. (Folder SS)
  - Portraits of Charles H. McCloskie, Alfred L. Malabre, Lester D. Mapes, Arthur B. Maurice, Robert Maverick, Frederick W. Meert, Dudley S. Morgan, C. B. Murdock, David T. Nelson, and Francis D. Neville (Folder TT)
  - Portraits of Thomas E. Oliver, Earl D. Osborn, Scott H. Paradise, Maurice Pate, William A. Percy, Philip S. Platt, William Babcock Poland, Francis H. Potter, Philip B. K. Potter, and Henry S. Pratt (Folder UU)
  - Portraits of Lewis Richards, Mr. Richardson, Gardner Richardson, A. B. Ruddock, James A. St. Amour, S. S. Seward, Jr., Millard K. Shaler, John L. Simpson, Richard H. Simpson, Robinson Smith, William H. Sperry, T. Harwood Stacy, F. Dorsey Stephens, Gilchrist B. Stockton, Carlos H. Stone, and William W. Stratton (Folder VV)
  - Portraits of E. Coppée Thurston, Frederick C. Thwaits, Clare M. Torrey, William Hallam Tuck, Julius A. Van Hee, John Brodhead Van Schaick, Marquis de Villalobar, M. van Volenhoven, Robert H. Warren, Laurence C. Wellington, Almon C. Whiting, Brand Whitlock, Caspar Whitney, Francis C. Wickes, Edgar Williams, Robert Withington, and Carl A. Young (Folder WW)
  - Prints of relief ships (Box 635, Folder XX-BBB)
  - Prints of relief ships (Box 636, Folder CCC-GGG)
  - Prints of relief ships (Box 637, Folder HHH-KKK)
  - Prints of relief ships (Box 638, Folder LLL-RRR)
  - Portraits of French children from Nancy (Box 639, Folder SSS)
  - Individual and group portraits of Belgian children (Folder TTT)
  - Album of prints of Herbert Hoover made by Elisabeth, Queen of the Belgians (Folder UUU)
  - Album of postcards of the orphanage at Charleroi, Belgium (Folder VVV)
  - Album of printed reproductions of scenes of Commission for Relief in Belgium operations in Belgium (Folder WWW)
  - Album of postcards of Belgian cities and cultural and social activities (Folder XXX)
  - Album of printed reproductions of drawings by H. Lemaire of officials of the Commission for Relief in Belgium and Comité National de Secours et d'Alimentation (Box 640, Folder YYY)
  - Album of contact prints from lantern slides of scenes of Commission for Relief in Belgium operations in Belgium (Folder ZZZ)
  - Postcards, issued by Amies de la Dentelle, of Belgian lacemakers at work. Includes postcards from American Clearing House, Paris (Folder AAAA)
  - Prints of German passes (Folder BBBB)
  - Prints and signatures of the members of the Comité De Secours et d'Alimentation de la Province de Liège (Folder CCCC)
  - Prints of Dutch native foodstuff and piece of bread being analyzed for its nutrition value (Folder DDDD)
  - Prints of Belgian supervisors including Griffin R. Barry, Charles Thomas Bayliss, Theo Becker, C. G. Bowden, Henry Percy Bradford, W. L. Brown, P. H. Chadbourn, Albert Willard Clark, Morris W. Croll, H. F. Cutler, Joseph Frank B. Erdlets, John A. Gade, F. H. Gallor, and Dudley Benjamin Gunn (Folder EEEE)
  - Print of Rotterdam Office staff (Folder FFFF)
  - Prints of miscellaneous scenes of Commission for Relief in Belgium staff members in groups, Commission for Relief in Belgium offices, and scenes of Commission for Relief in Belgium operations (Box 641, Folder GGGG)
  - Prints of miscellaneous and unidentified scenes of World War I (Folder HHHH)
  - Miscellaneous negatives and contact prints from lantern slides (Folder IIII)
  - Lantern slides (5" x 8") of Albert I, King of the Belgians; Elisabeth, Queen of the Belgians; James W. Gerard; Hugh Gibson; Herbert Hoover; Cardinal D. J. Mercier; Henry Van Dyke; Marquis de Villalobar; Commission for Relief in Belgium staff members in groups; relief ships; loading and unloading operations; relief distribution; Belgian refugees; military operations; scenic views in Belgium; flour sacks; caricatures; proclamations; and documents (Box 642)
  - Lantern slides (3" x 5") of miscellaneous and unidentified scenes
  - Lantern slides (3" x 5") of Herbert Hoover; Cardinal D. J. Mercier; Albert I, King of the Belgians; Hugh Gibson; Marquis de Villalobar; Elisabeth, Queen of the Belgians; Robert Arrowsmith; Walter Hines Page; James W. Gerard; Henry Van Dyke; unidentified individuals; Commission for Relief in Belgium staff members in groups; Commission for Relief in Belgium offices; and scenes of relief distribution (Box 643)
  - Lantern slides (3" x 5") of relief ships, loading and unloading operations, and Belgian refugees (Box 644)
  - Lantern slides (3" x 5") of World War I military scenes, war damage, and scenic views of Belgium and France (Box 645)
  - Lantern slides (3" x 5") of proclamations, documents, and text accompanying slide shows (Box 646)
  - Lantern slides (3" x 5") of caricatures, cartoons, posters, drawings, insignia, medals, maps, and flour sacks (Box 647)
- INDEX CARD FILE, n.d.
  - Alphabetical sequence (Box 648-652)
  - Chronological sequence (Box 653-657)